哥倫比亞三星電影集團公司  榮譽出品
三星影業
出品
安德魯·伯格曼 作品
尼古拉斯·凱奇
布裏吉特·芳達
傾 城 佳 話
從前在紐約  有個警察叫查理
Once upon a time in New York, there was a cop named Charlie.
他是個正派人  他的搭檔鮑也是
He was a very decent guy, as was his partner, Bo.
他是個很好的傾訴對像
He was a good listener.
他喜歡小孩
He loved kids.
他有耐心  也明辨事理
He had patience and common sense.
還很聰明
He was resourceful.
來吧  小心看路  來吧來吧  別停下
Come on, let's go. Watch your step. Come on, keep it moving.
好了夥計們  大家動起來  來吧  讓我過去
Okay, people, let's go. Let's go. Come on, let me get through.
讓我過去  讓一讓  好了  抓緊點走啊
Let me get through now. Make way, come on. Step lively now, come on.
他是個不錯的警察
He was just a good cop.
查理在皇后區土生土長  每天都過得很快樂
Charlie lived happily in Queens, where he was born and had lived all of his life.
- 嗨  查理  - 嗨  蘇 你好啊
- Yo, Charlie. - Jesu. How are you?
- 今天幹掉誰了  - 連根毫毛都沒傷害
- Kill anybody today? - Didn't even wound anybody.
最近沒什麼大事
Been really slow.
- 不想去看看你老婆嗎  - 她不喜歡在工作的時候被打擾
- You're not gonna see your wife? - No, she doesn't like me to surprise her at work.
查理和穆麗兒結了婚  她討厭皇后區
Charlie was married to Muriel. She hated Queens.
我不明白  如果他是探長或是臥底警察
I don't know. If he was a detective or an undercover cop...
起碼能穿得體面些
...at least he'd have decent clothes.
知道嗎  不過就算有了他也不會穿  他就愛穿制服
You know? But that's not for him. He's gotta wear the uniform.
我能理解  親愛的  你也不能對他要求太苛刻
I feel for you, honey. Because you got driving ambition.
我知道  我從來不給他太大壓力
I know. I never pushed him enough.
如果哪天他受賄了  我倒會說  好啊  有進步
If he was on the take, at least I'd say, "Okay. He has initiative."
我妹妹嫁給警察十年了  也沒見個好
My sister was married to a cop for 10 years. It's a no-win situation.
要麼他是老實的窮光蛋  要麼是徹夜不歸的騙子
Either they're honest and you're broke, or they're crooks and they never come home.
那你妹妹是怎麼想的呢
So your sister, what did she do?
她和他離了婚  嫁了一個電氣工程師  這才叫生財有道
She left the cop and married an electrician. That's your real money.
我都快沒耐心了  告訴你  我就是那種拜金女
I'm running out of patience. I tell you, I'm a person who needs money.
再來看看這位叫伊芳的女招待  她馬上就要得到壞消息了
And then there was Yvonne, a waitress, who's about to get some terrible news.
比亞西小姐  萬事達信用卡的記錄顯示  你已經欠款一萬兩千美元
Miss Biasi, according to your records here, you owe $12,000 on your MasterCard.
法官大人  這些錢都是我前夫花的
Your Honor, those charges were incurred by my ex-husband...
艾迪·比亞西是個演員  那時候我已經趕他走了
...Eddie Biasi, the actor, after I threw him out.
但是銀行並不知道你們離婚
The bank is not aware of your divorce.
我們還沒有辦離婚  但我告訴過他  必須把債務還清
Because we're not divorced yet. But I told him, "You have to tear up the credit cards."
他保證過
And he promised--
如果你們還沒有離婚  你就有償還債務的連帶義務
If you're not divorced yet, you're still liable for any and all debts your husband has incurred.
我已經拿定主意離婚了  您明白我的意思嗎  應該得到認可的
But I am divorced in my heart. You know? I mean, and that's what counts.
這在法律上得不到認可
Legally, that's not what counts.
您知道離婚要花多少錢嗎  我是說您離過婚嗎
But do you know how much it costs to get divorced? Have you ever been divorced?
大概沒有  當然沒有  自然不會有的事兒
Probably not. Probably not. Probably you haven't.
好人自然有上帝保佑平安
Probably you've had good luck your entire life.
而這點  我是正好相反
Which is great. Which is the opposite of me.
比亞西小姐  如果萬事達信用卡是以你的名義辦的  你就要負責
Miss Biasi, if the MasterCard is in your name, it's still your responsibility.
拜託拜託  我五年前從匹茲堡來紐約  夢想當個演員
Listen, please. I came to New York from Pittsburgh five years ago, to be an actress.
大學裏我演過『我們的小鎮』
I had done "Our Town" in college.
我告訴您  我主演的愛米麗  觀眾都被感動得嚎啕大哭了
Let me tell you something. Played Emily. People were crying buckets.
- 我確信他們會這樣  - 還需要別的什麼嗎
- I'm sure they were. - Will there be anything else?
因此我來到紐約  後來我遇到了艾迪
So I come to New York, and I meet Eddie.
告訴你什麼叫倒霉吧  法官大人  開始的時候  他令我十分感動
Talk about the worst luck of all. Your Honor, he swept me off my feet.
他送我鮮花  帶我兜風  請我去高檔餐館吃飯
He bought me flowers, he took me on taxi rides, and real restaurants.
有亞麻桌布  美酒和漂亮的燈飾  您能想像嗎
With linen and wine and good lighting, you know?
一切都很完美  直到他變成一個病態的騙子
Everything was so perfect, except he turned out to be this pathological liar.
我居然相信了他說的每句話
And I believed every word he said...
或許就是因為我太輕信別人了  您明白嗎
...because I used to have all this faith in people. You know?
所以  所以  怎麼說呢  簡而言之
So.... So, like, in short...
我還能有什麼選擇啊
...what are my options here?
「破產」
查理  穆麗兒  伊芳生活在同一座城市裏
Charlie, Muriel and Yvonne all lived in a city...
這裏的人們每天都盼望出現奇跡
...where people prayed for miracles every day.
比方說  買中六千四百萬美元的彩票
Like winning the $64 million lottery.
我是安吉爾
My name is Angel.
下面你將要看到的故事  絕大部分是真實的
The story you're about to see, well, it's pretty much all true.
我昨晚做夢了
I had a dream last night.
夢見玩老虎機  轉到三個櫻桃  然後  它們又不是櫻桃了
I was playing a slot machine, and I got three cherries, but they wasn't cherries.
它們變成了我死去的爸爸的笑臉  這是徵兆
They were my father's face, the face of my dead father. It's a sign.
你不是討厭你老爸麼
But you hated your father.
沒錯  我是討厭他  但徵兆就是徵兆
Makes no difference I hated him. A sign is a sign.
我知道你認為我在扯淡  但我告訴你我們會中彩
I know you think I'm nuts, but I tell you, we're gonna win.
我沒說你在扯淡
I didn't say you were nuts.
我只是說中彩的幾率那是相當小
I just said the odds of us winning the lottery are not overwhelming.
你又不是不知道  挺簡單的事
And you know what? It's okay.
在皇后區  單居室的住房可不是我的目標
One bedroom in Queens is not my idea of living.
在皇后區  單居室已經挺好了
One bedroom in Queens is fine.
如果我們有孩子  孩子  那就另當別論了
If we had kids.... If we had kids, it would be another story.
- 我們沒錢養孩子  - 我們當然有錢養孩子
- We don't have the money to have kids. - Of course we have the money to have kids.
警察能養孩子  消防員也能養孩子
Cops have kids. Firemen have kids.
如果只許有錢人養孩子  那還要公立學校幹嘛
If only rich people had kids, there wouldn't be public schools.
查理  你把彩票給我買了就行了  拜託
Charlie, just get the ticket this morning, please.
她還當真了  你應該明確告訴她
She gotta get real. You gotta tell her:
作為老公  每天早出晚歸辛苦工作  就為賺錢養家
"I'm the man. I'm out here every day, getting it done...
男人就那麼好當嗎  要讓你老婆懂得這點
...getting paid, bringing it home." You know what I'm saying? She gotta listen to you.
- 你開玩笑吧  - 就等我兩分鐘
- You can't be serious. - It takes two minutes.
我都快餓死了  夥計
I'm starving, man.
- 哎  各位  警察辦案  大家靠邊站  - 別  別這樣
- Hey, people, this is police business, step aside. - Bo, Bo.
- 只耽誤兩分鐘  - 對不起  對不起
- It'll take two minutes. - Sorry. Sorry.
我們得永遠呆在這兒啦  要吃巨無霸漢堡還得走五個街區
This is gonna take forever. Then the Burger King's another five blocks.
- 那就去馬路對面那家餐廳  我們沒去過那  - 什麼  那地方  噢  不
- So we'll eat across the street. We never went there. - What, that place? Oh, no.
- 你去什麼鬼地方了  - 昨天告訴你了  薩爾
- Where the hell were you? - I told you yesterday, Sal.
說過五次了  個人私事  非去不可  嗨  卡洛爾
Five times. A personal matter, I couldn't help it. Hi, Carol.
你遲到兩小時  得從你工資裏扣
You are two hours late. It comes off your paycheck.
什麼  你知道我還有多少天病假嗎
What? Do you know how many sick days I have coming?
如果你想請病假  就生病去  如果沒病  你就得幹活
You want a sick day, get sick. If you're healthy, you work.
給我拿杯咖啡來
Get me some coffee.
- 在你頭上  小可愛  - 謝謝
- On your head, sweetie pie. - Thanks.
- 那傢伙嘴皮挺會翻的  啊  - 是啊  像個魔鬼教官
- That guy sets a nice tone here, huh? - Yeah, like a drill sergeant.
咖啡來了
Here we go.
- 你們倆要咖啡嗎  - 是的
- You guys want some coffee? - Please.
咖啡
Please.
- 你們想要點什麼  - 奶酪漢堡  越橘汁鬆餅
- You guys know what you want? - Cheeseburger deluxe, medium.
這會兒我想來份藍莓鬆餅
And while I'm waiting, a blueberry muffin.
好的
All right.
你呢  警官
And you, officer?
你要推薦龍蝦大拼盤嗎
You recommend the lobster thermidor?
這真有趣  我是說  我都快笑死了
That's really funny. I mean, I think I'm just gonna die laughing.
我一整天都沒好事  這是我今天最好的享受了
The kind of day I've had so far. I can't even tell you what a treat this is.
你今天過得很糟糕嗎
You've had a bad day?
- 想好了就叫我  - 一份肉丸三明治
- Call me when you're ready. - A meatball sandwich.
是的  我就來這個
Really. That's what I want.
- 肉丸子  - 肉丸子
- Meatball? - Meatball.
你還真敢吃這個啊  警官
You are very brave, officer.
她喜歡你  真的
She likes you. Yeah, she really likes you.
我只是想讓她高興起來
I was trying to cheer her up.
剛收到報告  有個裸體男人從商店跑到了街上
We got a store alarm on Spring Street and a naked man in traffic on Sullivan.
好吧  我飽了
Well, I'm full.
見鬼  我都快餓死了
Shit, I'm gonna starve to death.
- 這次你付賬  - 行
- Your turn for the check. - Okay.
- 小姐  我們得走了  要出去檢查  - 辦完所有事情才能吃飯嗎
- Miss, we gotta run, so we'll just take a check. - After that whole routine?
- 指揮電台不再發佈消息就行  - 哪兒  在哪兒  我放哪兒了
- When those radios go off.... - Where, where? Where did I--?
謝謝
Thank you.
好吧  兩杯咖啡加稅  雙人份額
All right, so that's two coffees plus taxes. Two even.
噢  天吶  怎麼沒錢了
Oh, jeez. I'm short.
- 算了  警官  不記帳了  - 不行  我有付賬的錢
- Fine, officer. No charge. - No, I have the check.
就是不夠付小費的
I just don't have enough for a tip.
- 我能活下去  - 我可不能不給小費
- I'll live. - I can't not leave a tip.
那就給吧
So leave a tip.
彩票如何
A lottery ticket?
就我這運氣  別開玩笑了  趕緊走吧  去把樹上的貓救下來吧  該幹嘛幹嘛去吧
With my luck? Be serious. No. Go, get the cat out of the tree or whatever it is that you do.
不  那是消防員的工作
No, that would be the Fire Department.
- 快點 查理 走啦  - 就一會兒
- Come on, Charlie, let's go. - In a second.
聽著  我有個主意  你叫什麼
Listen, I got an idea. What's your name?
伊芳  伊芳  我是查理·蘭  我們現在是合夥人了
Yvonne? Yvonne, I'm Charlie Lang, and we're partners.
如果我中彩了  我就回來分你一半的錢
If this ticket wins, I'll come back tomorrow and split the proceeds.
如果沒中彩  我還是會回來補給你小費  你認為如何
If it doesn't, I'll still come back and leave you a tip. What do you think?
- 我想我不會再見到你了  - 你明天會見到我的
- I think I'm never gonna see you again. - You'll see me tomorrow.
- 好啊  我就在這  - 說定了
- Well, I'll be here. - You've got a deal.
好了  再玩五分鐘
All right, five more minutes.
- 查理  - 怎麼啦
- Charlie. - Yeah.
我叫了中餐  上來
I ordered Chinese. Come up.
- 一分鐘  - 你要挨老婆打了嗎
- In a minute. - What, are you whipped?
不  才不會  我只是盡盡成年人的責任而已 下一個擊球手
No, I'm not whipped. I've got adult responsibilities. Next batter.
嗨  擊球  擊球  擊球
Hey, batter, batter, batter.
漂亮  我出局了  球在哪兒
That's it. I'm out of here. Where's the ball?
蘇
Jesu!
我來了  媽
I'm coming, Mom.
- 你要挨打了嗎  蘇  - 她是我老媽  沒得商量
- Are you whipped, Jesu? - It's my mother, there's no comparison.
- 明天見  小子  - 晚安  查理
- See you tomorrow, kiddo. - Yeah. Night, Charlie.
昨天晚上你去做手術了嗎
Did you, by any chance, have surgery last night?
你說這個嗎  不  這只是個隱型胸罩
You mean these? No. No, this is just a prosthetic bra....
查理  求你別在我面前幹這個  噁心死了
Charlie, come on. Don't do that next to me. That's disgusting.
- 我只是泡泡腳  - 不行
- I'm just soaking my feet. - Please.
不敢相信這真是你
I just can't believe it's you.
是這樣  不是因為你  而是它的功效
Well, it's not. But it's gonna be.
- 什麼時候這也惹著你了  - 從現在開始  行嗎
- Since when did this bother you? - Since now, okay?
噢  上帝  你把水弄得到處都是
Oh, God! Charlie, now you're spilling water all over the place.
我想我該叫紅十字會  告訴他們  我們這兒是災區
Maybe I should call the Red Cross. I'll tell them we're a federal disaster area. God!
我有一些更大的  下班後我就戴它們
As a matter of fact, I have some a couple of sizes larger that I'll change into after work.
- 查理  - 什麼
- Charlie. - What?
你覺得我把胸部弄一下怎麼樣
You think I should get my boobs done?
- 弄什麼  - 沒錯  你懂的  隆胸
- Done? - Yeah, you know, enlarged.
感覺要好些
So I could be like that.
什麼  你瘋了  這也太誇張了吧
What, are you nuts? It seems so extreme.
- 就當我沒說  - 我只是不懂你在想什麼
- Forget it. - I just don't think you need it.
行啦
Forget it.
瞧  問題是我已經破產
Look, the problem is that I had to declare bankruptcy.
我的信用卡被拿走了  什麼時候才能拿回來
My MasterCard got taken away. What I wanna know is when I'm gonna be able to get it back.
我有什麼選擇呢
What are my chances?
- 一年一萬五千美元以下  信用卡  - 要我和他們說嗎  好吧
- Under 15,000 a year? MasterCard. - Shall I speak to them? Love to.
嗯  是嗎
Yeah? Well....
等等  喔
Wait. I see.
好  謝謝你  我也這麼認為
Well, thank you. That's what I thought.
- 他們怎麼說  - 基本沒可能  我是沒機會了
- What did they say? - Slim to none. Those are my chances.
樂透的頭獎已經滾動到了六千四百萬美元
Well, the lotto jackpot has grown to over $64 million.
廣告後我們再公佈中獎號碼
We'll check the winning numbers when we return.
- 你選錯號碼了  - 錯了嗎
- You got the numbers wrong. - Wrong?
- 我們的結婚紀念日是27號  不是26號 - 那為什麼我們總是在26號慶祝呀
- Our anniversary is on the 27th, not on the 26th. - We always celebrate on the 26th.
我們是26號辦的手續  27號辦的喜酒
We got the license on the 26th. We got married on the 27th.
- 那我們為什麼不在26號辦喜酒  - 我不知道  也許因為什麼風俗
- So why do we go out on the 26th? - I don't know, maybe it's custom.
你看  事實上  我特別告訴了你準確的週年紀念日
Look, the fact is that I specifically told you our anniversary.
任何人都會記得他們結婚的日子
To anybody with any sense in their heads, that means the day they got married.
- 對不起  親愛的  - 26  64  84
- I am sorry, darling. - 26, 64, 84.
他說26了嗎
Did he say 26?
重複一下中獎號碼
Those numbers, again, are...
6  12  16  26  64  84
...6, 12, 16, 26, 64, 84.
- 什麼  - 我們中了  我們中了頭獎
- What? - We won. We got the jackpot.
- 令人難以相信 - 我們有錢了  有錢了  有錢了
- That's unbelievable. - We're rich. We're rich. We're rich.
- 頭獎嗎  - 我們有錢了  有錢了  有錢了
- The jackpot? - We're rich, rich, rich.
- 我們有了什麼  寶貝兒  - 奇跡隨著烤火雞降臨
- What are we having, honey? - BLT down with turkey bacon.
- 奇跡突然從天而降  - 當然是奇跡突然從天而降
- Any Miracle Whip? - Of course I have Miracle Whip.
不論生活怎麼變化  也只是某些事情  某些標準
No matter how broke I am, there's just certain things, certain standards.
你生命裏必須擁有一些不變的東西  永遠不變
You have to have things in your life that are stable, that are permanent, eternal.
- 夾心餅  脆餅  - 沒錯
- Oreos. Smuckers. - Exactly.
- 謝謝  - 還想要點什麼嗎
- Thank you. - Will there be anything else?
還會有什麼呢
Will there be anything else?
不會再有什麼了
There'll never be anything else.
天啊  我討厭這樣  我心都涼了
God, I hate this. I feel bankrupt.
什麼
What?
噢  上帝  奧爾巴尼保齡球隊是同樣的號碼
Oh, God. A bowling team from Albany had the same numbers.
- 他們分走了九百萬  - 為什麼我並不感到驚訝呢
- They get 9 million. - Why am I not surprised?
- 這個球隊有多少人啊  - 我不清楚  大概有十二個人吧
- Well, how many are there on the team? - I don't know. Twelve guys is the average league.
好  他們是一人一份  還是整個球隊算一份
Okay, well, do each of these guys get a piece, or do you consider them all as one?
穆麗兒  穆麗兒  青筋  從你脖子上暴出來了
Muriel, Muriel. The veins, they're bulging out of your neck.
你看起來像是個瘋婆子
You look like a psycho.
什麼  那好  是嗎
What? All right. Yeah.
噢  我的上帝  那些球員  謝天謝地  他們只算一份
Oh, my God. Okay, the bowlers, thank God, they only count as one.
這還是有十六個人選了同樣的號碼  上帝呀
But that's 16 people that picked these numbers. Oh, God.
我們只有十六分之一
That only leaves us with...
才四百萬
...four million.
夠我們生活了  對吧
We could live on that, right?
噢  是啊  是啊
Oh, yeah, yeah.
再少一點也足夠了
We could live on less, even.
讓我們祈禱別再有人摻合進來  這樣就沒人分我們的錢了
Let's just pray to God that nobody else calls in, so we don't have to split it with them.
怎麼啦
What?
幹嘛
怎麼啦  你讓我渾身不自在
What, Charlie? You're making me nervous. What?
親愛的
Honey...
我有句話要對你說
...I've got something to tell you.
- 一個完全陌生的人  查理  - 我欠她小費
- A complete stranger? Charlie. - I owed her a tip.
小費  兩百萬美元的小費  得了吧
A tip? Two million dollars? Come on.
我從來沒想過我們會中彩  親愛的
I never thought we'd win, darling. I never thought we'd win.
但我們確實中彩了  就像我說的
But we did win, just like I told you we were going to.
但按你選的號碼  我們根本就中不了
But if we'd used your numbers, we wouldn't have won.
別這樣  別這樣  查理  你我都知道
Don't do that. Don't do that, Charlie. Because you know and I know...
我死去的父親托夢給我了  通過老虎機  暗示我我會贏
...that in my dream, my dead father came to me through the slot machine.
在他眼裏有美元符號和4
And in his eyes there were dollar signs and a "4" in place of the pupil.
好了  查理  你想褻瀆我對父親的懷念嗎
Come on, Charlie. You wanna blemish his sacred memory?
太荒唐了  你爸是個怪人  他向雞禱告
That's ridiculous. He was a nut job, your father, he prayed to chickens.
他希望我們能有四百萬
He wants us to have the 4 million.
哎  你想想  如果他認為我們只該拿一半
My God, do you think if he intended us to have half...
那應該是2  不會是4
...wouldn't there be a "2" instead of a "4" inside the eyeballs?
那樣做不對
It's not the right thing.
不對  查理  你在說什麼鬼話
The right thing? Charlie, what the hell is that?
你一直在為別人做正確的事情
You've been doing the right thing your whole entire life for everybody else.
只要這一次  也為我們倆做一次正確的事情
Just this once, please, do the right thing for us.
我答應她了
I gave her my word.
查理
Charlie....
- 老公  你愛我嗎  - 我當然愛你
- Honey, do you love me? - Of course I love you.
回絕她  回絕她  她不會察覺  就當是為我
Then stiff her. Stiff her and smell the flowers. For me.
- 如果是你會怎麼做  - 買下尼克斯球隊
- What would you do? - I'd buy the Knicks.
我說的是那個姑娘
I mean, about the girl.
我會帶她去公園  讓她看我打球
I'd take her to the Garden so she could watch me play.
我會小心翼翼  然後轉彎抹角給她建議
I'd start myself as a very small, round forward.
這麼說你同意穆麗兒的看法  分她一半的錢就是傻子
So you agree with Muriel, right? Giving her half is crazy?
要是買不成球隊  我也要買整個賽季的球票
If I can't have the Knicks, I want those season tickets...
你就可以欣賞傑克·尼克爾森和斯派克·李  而服務生給你送上零食
...where you sit on the floor with Jack Nicholson and Spike Lee. And the waiters bring you food.
- 說話得算數   - 是啊  弄套音響系統
- A promise is a promise. - And one of those stereo systems...
你在家中房子裏隨便哪個角落都能聽
...that you can hear in every room in your house.
你瞧  這樣你就用不著提著唱片機到處跑了
You see, that way you don't have to be carrying around that boom box with you.
我可以告訴她  我只中了五千塊  我能做到這點
I could tell her I just won 5,000. I could do that.
是啊  是啊  你當然可以啦
Yeah, yeah, you could.
這樣如何  賽季套票  音響系統  馬自達GL6
So, what's that? Season tickets, stereo system, Mazda GL6?
- 我不能那樣做  不應該說謊  - 遊艇  我從沒上過遊艇
- I couldn't do that. I couldn't just lie like that. - A boat. I've never even been in a boat.
- 你在聽嗎  - 我瞭解你  你會做你該做的事情
- Come on, are you listening to me? - I know you, man. You'll do the appropriate thing.
- 什麼意思  - 我不知道  這是你的事兒
- Which is? - I don't know. That's your field.
來了  一條金槍魚  嫩炒蛋  法式麵包  檸檬茶
Okay. So we have tuna on whole wheat, one scrambled soft, toast crisp, tea with lemon.
- 糖罐在你桌上  - 謝謝
- Sugar's at your table. - Thanks.
- 都還好嗎  - 是啊  謝謝
- Everything okay here? Good, good. - Yeah, thanks.
早上好
Morning.
- 你還真來了  - 我說過我會回來
- You're back. - I said I'd be back.
- 咖啡  - 不用  謝謝  其實我來只是想
- Coffee? - No, thanks. Actually, I just wanted to--
我真的想為昨天的事道歉  我太粗魯了
I really wanna apologize for yesterday. I was so rude.
但昨天我確實過得很糟糕  從早到晚
It's just that it was pretty much the worst day of my life, from start to finish.
- 伊芳  快點  上菜  - 嘮叨個沒完
- Yvonne, let's go, wake up. - Impossible today.
- 我嘮叨  伊芳還指望這兒呢  - 別說閒話
- I'm impossible? Yvonne's dreaming here. - Quit the socializing.
別急著走  我得向你道歉
Don't go anywhere, I want to apologize to you in detail.
好了  你的套餐來了  沃爾特
Okay. Western for you, Walter.
給你一些像你老媽做的麥片
And for Timothy, some nice oatmeal like Mom used to make.
我老媽從來不做麥片  她這輩子都沒做過飯
My mother never made oatmeal in her life. My mother never made food in her life.
血色瑪麗雞尾酒她倒是做過  還有白俄羅斯
Bloody Marys, she made. White Russians....
- 但她挺有個性的  - 伊梅爾達·馬科斯也一樣
- But she had a great personality. - So did Imelda Marcos.
- 嗯  她生了個好兒子  不是嗎  - 你很好  你知道吧
- Well, she produced a nice son, right? - You're okay, you know that?
慢用
Eat.
- 他得了艾滋 對嗎  - 是啊  好幾年了  一周來兩次
- He's got it, huh? - Yeah, a couple of years. Come in twice a week.
他的情況越來越糟了  你知道嗎  從醫院出來
He's really starting to go downhill, though, you know? In and out of the hospital....
什麼世道啊  真是的
What a world, huh? Really.
我們每時每刻都要慶幸自己還活著  而不是抱怨
Makes you wanna appreciate every moment, you know, not be petty or spiteful.
- 我能理解你  - 伊芳
- I know just what you mean. - Yvonne.
說到這兒
Speaking of which....
我這有張九塊五毛三的賬單  但錢櫃裏卻沒有這九塊五毛三
What I have here is a check for $9.53. What I do not have is the $9.53.
他說他到車裏拿錢包去了
He went to get his wallet out of the car. He said--
絕不能讓他們出門
Never let them out the door.
- 你以為我是搞慈善的嗎  - 對不起  我錯了
- What am I running here, a soup kitchen? - I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
當然是你的錯  這九塊五毛三從你工資裏扣  給我拿杯咖啡來
You sure did, gorgeous. And the $9.53, it gets deducted from your check. Bring me some coffee.
讓我來
Let me.
慢用
Enjoy.
這才叫咖啡呢
Now, that's coffee.
嗯  我們剛才說到哪兒了
So, what'll it be?
- 他們確實  他們真的  - 真的很難得
- They're actually.... They're right.... - Amazing, but true.
我們現在有哈密瓜  還有柚子  那麼
We are all out of cantaloupe, and the grapefruit's all dried out, so....
不  我不餓
No, I'm not hungry.
我想說的是  想給你一樣東西
The thing is, I got something for you.
- 給我的  - 這只是個小東西
- For me? - It's just, you know, a trifle.
可以嗎
May I?
把這個小鏈子繫在你的眼鏡腿上
It's one of those little strings that you connect to your glasses...
然後把眼鏡掛在脖子上
...so that they hang around your neck.
這樣你隨時就會知道它們在哪兒了
And that way you'll know where they are. At all times.
這簡直是我收到的最好的禮物
This is the nicest thing anyone's ever gotten me.
- 我都希望不是  - 差不多是
- I certainly hope not. - It's close.
你確定不吃點什麼嗎  咖啡要麼
You sure that I can't get you anything? Like a coffee or tea?
來杯不含咖啡因的吧  其實今天我心跳得太快了
Decaf, please. I've reached my target heart rate for the day.
不含咖啡因的
Decaf it is.
- 呃  你運氣不好嗎  - 說出來你都不信
- So, you've had bad luck? - Unbelievable.
十一歲的時候  我養的小狗死於毒癥
When I was 11, my dog died of parvo.
至今我仍然不知道那到底是什麼毒癥
I still don't even know, to this day, what parvo is.
我嫁錯了人  我的意思是這個人毛病真多 我運氣真不好
I married the wrong man. I mean the wrong, by a lot, man.
你能想像嗎
You know?
現在  我負擔不起離婚的費用  直到昨天
Now I can't afford to get divorced. I mean, except for yesterday....
知道嗎  我已經習慣走霉運了
You know, I'm used to my luck.
但昨天  我來上班前  剛被法院宣佈破產
But yesterday, I actually went bankrupt before I came into work, which was....
這就是為什麼我對你態度不好
That's why I was so rude to you.
- 你破產了  - 是啊
- You went bankrupt? - Yep.
- 看  警官送的  - 真體貼  親愛的
- Look. From the officer. - That's sweet, honey.
- 等等  - 什麼
- Wait. - What?
說一下我們的協議吧
About our little agreement.
雙倍小費  或是彩票獎金的一半
Double the tip, or half of what I won in the lottery.
- 那個協議  - 由你任選一項
- That agreement. - How about we make it your choice.
選項一  雙倍小費  選項二  彩票獎金的一半
Door one, double the tip. Door two, half of what I won in the lottery.
讓我選  好吧
My choice? Okay.
管它了  我選二  我要一半獎金  要現錢
Whatever. I'll take door number two. I'll take half of the lottery. Pay up.
- 你確定  - 那當然
- You're sure? - Positive.
- 我也希望你選這個  - 我想也是  下次好運  彩票沒中  對吧
- I was hoping you'd say that. - I'll bet you were. Better luck next time, right?
其實  我們  我們這次運氣就很好
Actually, we were.... We were pretty lucky.
- 真的嗎  你中了多少錢  - 我們中了多少錢
- Really? Did you win something? - We won something.
好吧  我們中了多少錢
All right. We won something? What did we win?
四百萬美元
Four million dollars.
- 你幹嘛這樣  - 怎麼了
- Why are you doing this? - What?
開這種可惡的玩笑
This sick joke.
- 不 這不是玩笑  - 這不是開玩笑嗎
- No, it's not a joke. - This is not a joke?
- 不是  - 不是嗎  你剛才說什麼來著
- No. - No? What you're telling me....
你對我說什麼  你真的
What you're saying to me.... You really....
- 怎麼  你以為我想拿你尋開心嗎  - 是的  我是那麼想的
- What, you think I'd make this up? - Yes, yes, I do.
我沒有  我們中獎了
I'm not. We won.
彩票  紐約州的  樂透彩票
The lottery? The New York State--? The "lottery" lottery?
真的是紐約樂透彩票  四百萬美元
The actual New York State lottery? Four million dollars?
是的  分到四百萬  昨天晚上開的獎  原本可能更多
Yes, 4 million is our share. It happened last night. It would've been more...
但奧爾巴尼保齡球隊也中彩了
...except a bowling team from Albany called in...
他們從獎池裏分了九百萬獎金  不管怎麼說  我們還是中彩了
...they took about 9 million out of the pot, but we won.
你是說  你真要和我平分獎金
And you're telling me that you're actually going to split it with me?
說話得算數
A promise is a promise.
噢  我的上帝呀
Oh, my God.
- 你沒事吧  - 噢  我的上帝呀
- You all right? - Oh, my God.
噢  我的上帝  噢  我的上帝  噢  我的上帝呀
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
我簡直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
現在我知道為什麼我要經歷那麼多糟糕的事情了  現在我知道為什麼了
Now I know why all these bad things happened. I know why now.
這真是太不可思議了  令人難以置信的事情怎麼可能發生在我身上
It's so this stupendous, phenomenal, unbelievably great thing could happen to me.
因為我承受過如此多的晦氣  太可怕了  這又算得了什麼呢
Because I had such bad, horrible, horrible luck before, no one would even mind.
誰要奶油冰淇淋
Who wants ice cream on their pie?
- 我要  - 誰要餡餅
- I do! - Who wants pie?
謝謝你
Thank you.
等一等  我不能接受這個  我不能
Wait a minute. I can't accept this, can I? I mean....
我不能接受這個  我是說  我想  我非常期待  但是
I can't accept this. I mean, I want to, so desperately I want to, but....
但是在我看來  在我看來
But there's this part of me, this neurotic part of me--
接受吧
Accept it.
- 我能嗎  - 接受吧  我希望你接受它
- How can I? - Accept it. I want you to have it.
- 真心實意的  - 伊芳  接受吧
- With all my heart. - Yvonne, take it.
穆麗兒  兩百萬也不是個小數目了
Muriel, $2 million is still an enormous amount of money.
你應該被送到精神病院關上一輩子  再也不讓出來
You should be committed to an insane asylum for the rest of your natural life.
他們應該給你穿上拘束病服
They should put you in a straitjacket and take you to the loony bin...
然後把你送到被曝光的斯塔登島瘋人院去
...on Staten Island that Geraldo Rivera is always exposing.
你瞧  甜心  你當時不在場  好嗎
Now, look, sweetheart, you weren't there. Okay?
她有個顧客得了艾滋病  但她仍像天使一樣對待他
This girl, she's got customers with AIDS, and she treats them like an angel.
- 而她的老闆簡直是從地獄來的  - 那你幹嘛只給一半
- She's got a boss from hell. - Why did you stop at half?
你為什麼不全都給她
Why didn't you just give her all the money?
- 你別踩我的腳  - 你瞧  我們做的是正確的事情
- Would you get off my foot? - Look, we're doing the right thing.
你知道嗎  整個城市都會欽佩你  大家都會認識你  你就成名人啦
You know what? The whole city will admire you. Everybody will know you. You'll be a celebrity.
好吧  也許我能因此成為某些商品的代言人
Well, maybe I could get some commercial endorsements out of this.
當然可以  穆麗兒·蘭  一個有著金子般心腸的女人
Absolutely. "Muriel Lang, the woman with the heart of gold."
你可以代言洗髮香波  護髮素
You can endorse shampoos, conditioners...
指甲油  洗甲水
...nail polish, nail polish remover.
穆麗兒·蘭  一個有著金子般心腸的女人
"Muriel Lang, the woman with the heart of gold."
好  我得從這件事上得到些什麼
Well, I'd better get something out of this.
- 打保齡贏美元  打保齡贏美元  - 我要領我的支票  哈利
- Bowling for dollars. Bowling for dollars. - I want my check, Harry.
我要領我的支票
I want my check.
紐約最幸運的人們  現在聚集在曼哈頓
Some of New York's luckiest people gathered here in midtown Manhattan...
來領取他們高達六千四百萬美元的樂透彩票大獎
..here to stake their claim in the state's $64 million lotto jackpot.
於是你就承諾分給比亞西小姐一半的錢嗎
So you promised Miss Biasi if your ticket came in, you'd split it?
對  就當是小費
That's right. As a tip.
作為小費  我們採訪到一位警察給了女招待兩百萬美元的小費
As a tip? Hey. We got a cop that gave a waitress a $2 million tip.
我們正打算開我們自己的保齡球俱樂部
We're gonna open our own bowling alley.
- 你把他惹惱了  - 我把他惹惱了嗎  那下次你說得了
- You insulted the guy. - I insulted the guy? Next time, you talk.
- 我想在鄉下買個小別墅  - 對不起
- I'd like a little cottage in the country. - Excuse me.
- 對不起  對不起  - 蘭太太  談談你的感受
- Excuse me. Excuse me. - Mrs. Lang, how do you feel?
- 我才是蘭太太  - 蘭太太  你是蘭太太
- I'm Mrs. Lang. - Mrs. Lang? You're Mrs. Lang.
噢  我的上帝  這裏  這些是給您的
Oh, my God. Here. These are for you.
你真是難以置信的好女人  居然分了兩百萬美元
What an incredible woman you are to give $2 million...
- 給一個你不認識的人  - 你完全想像不到
- ...to someone you don't even know. - You have no idea.
蘭太太  蘭太太  你介意你丈夫和一個陌生人平分這四百萬獎金嗎
Mrs. Lang, do you have any trouble with the fact your husband split $4 million with a stranger?
一點也不  在我的理髮店  我總是被稱為
Not at all. In the beauty parlor that I work, I've always been known as...
穆麗兒·蘭  一個有著金子般心腸的女人
...Muriel Lang, the woman with the heart of gold.
如果這裏有人要做廣告  比方說德拉瑞思洗髮水
And if there are any sponsors out there, like Denorex...
正好是我用的那種  因為
...which I personally use, you know, because the air in my--
諸位
Guys!
我們現在要為中獎者拍一張合影照
We've got to get the winners together for a group picture.
- 比亞西小姐  這些錢你怎麼花呢  - 買一輛新車  還是買更大的房子
- Miss Biasi, what are you gonna do with the money? - A new car? Bigger apartment?
我還沒想過  事情發生的太突然了
I haven't thought about it yet. It's so unexpected, you know?
說話得算數  這沒什麼
Well, a promise is a promise.
穆麗兒·蘭  一個有著金子般心腸的女人
Muriel Lang, woman with the heart of gold.
噢  我以前做過演員  但不太成功
Oh, actress briefly, but it didn't work out.
德拉瑞思洗髮水  能清除每一個人的頭皮屑
Denorex. Works out each individual dandruff.
- 蘭警官  你還會留在警察局工作嗎  - 我會把警察局買下來
- Officer Lang, you gonna stay on the force? - I'm gonna buy the force.
- 伊芳  - 開一家伊芳餐館  已經想好了
- Yvonne? - So it's "Yvonne" already?
- 這是你收到最多的一筆小費吧  - 那當然
- Is this the biggest tip you've ever received? - Definitely.
穆麗兒
Muriel.
- 你以前中過獎嗎  - 從來沒有
- Have you ever won anything before? - Never.
- 從來沒有  - 大家都笑得開心點
- Never. - Big smile, everybody.
「警察給了女招待兩百萬美元小費」
她沒有一點品位  那裝扮  看起來像六十年代似的
Come on, she has no taste. That outfit, it looked like it came from the '60s.
我覺得她看上去挺樸素的
I thought she looked just fine.
她只是個女招待  幹嘛打扮得花枝招展的
She's not flashy. She's just a waitress.
我是做美容的  相信我的判斷  行嗎
Beauty is my business, defer to my judgment, okay?
噢  上帝呀  班德斯名品店  親愛的  有錢來這兒是真是太好了
My God, it's Bendel's. Oh, honey, what a feeling it is to come here with money.
上帝保佑你們
「我是盲人  退伍老兵  請幫幫我」
God bless you.
不要隨便給乞丐錢好不好
Would you stop giving it away to every bum on the street.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
- 現在我真的很高興  - 我也很高興  親愛的
- Now I'm happy. - I'm glad, sweetheart.
- 現在我終於心滿意足了 - 我也為你高興  親愛的
- Now I'm at peace with myself. -I'm glad, sweetheart.
再去蒂凡尼珠寶店逛一下  那樣我就重生了
Just a quick stop at Tiffany's, and I'll be born again.
皮毛是動物的  人類不應該穿著
Fur's for animals, not for people.
對不起
Excuse me.
我是萬事達信用卡服務中心的埃莉諾·史密斯
This is Eleanor Smith of MasterCard credit services.
我們通知您一個好消息
We're calling with the happy news that you are now eligible...
伊芳·比亞西小姐已經被授予兩萬美元的信用額度
...Miss Yvonne Biasi, for a $20,000 line of credit.
若有需要  請撥打電話1-800-555-2000
Please call me at 1-800-555-2000.
- 高興死了 像到了天堂  - 嗨  伊芳  祝賀你獲獎
- I've died and gone to heaven. - Hi, Yvonne, congratulations on winning.
我是保羅  我想讓你用電線抽我屁股
My name is Paul, and I'd like you to spank my tushy with a wire brush.
噢  上帝呀  真噁心
Oh, my God. That's disgusting.
看來我得換電話號碼了
I've got to change my number.
你好  我是伊芳  請在嗶聲後留言
Hello, this is Yvonne. At the beep, please leave a message.
喂  親愛的
Hello? Sweetheart?
我打賭你在家
I'll bet you're there.
我知道  我知道你因為我花光了錢很生我的氣
I know, I know. You're mad at me because I emptied the checking account.
- 但是  寶貝兒  我可以解釋  - 滾出我的生活  艾迪
- But, baby, I can explain. - Stay out of my life, Eddie.
你果然在家  嗨  寶貝兒
You are there. Hi, baby.
你打電話來  就是為了我的彩票獎金吧
The only reason you're calling is you read about me and the lottery.
- 你休想  - 什麼  你中彩了嗎
- You want a piece of it. - What? You won something?
- 去死吧  - 別  寶貝兒  我說正經的
- Die. - No, baby. I'm serious.
我在城外  你說你中彩啦  這太好了
I've been out of town. What, the lottery, you said? That's fabulous.
你中了多少錢
You did good?
還不錯
I did all right.
那太好了  寶貝兒  沒有人比你更應該中獎  我說真的
Well, that's great, baby. Nobody deserves it more. I mean that.
這可是我的真心話
From the bottom of my heart.
- 喂  - 不要再給我打電話了
- Hello? - Please don't ever call me again.
- 你打算什麼時候退休  - 我沒打算退休
- So when are you retiring? - I'm not retiring.
- 是嗎  別逗了  - 我不打算退休  這是我的真實想法
- Yeah, right. - I'm not retiring. Get off my case.
你的幽默感去哪兒啦
Where's that sense of humor?
你會怎麼做  半夜三點有個傢伙打電話來
What would you do? Three in the morning, a guy calls...
說他拿槍頂著腦袋
...says he's holding a Luger to his head...
說除非你給他一千美元  否則他就扣動扳機
...unless you give him $1,000 he's pulling the trigger.
如果他半夜三點打給我  我就告訴他  隨你的便
If he called me at 3:00 in the morning, I'd tell him to go ahead.
- 真有這種事嗎  - 就在昨天晚上  都是彩票引起的
- That really happen? - Last night. This lottery thing....
明天又會有個什麼人  以什麼理由冒出來
From one day to the next, you become this other person.
- 太煩人了  - 我真同情你  夥計
- It's just weird. - I feel bad for you, baby.
我沒說中獎不好  我只是說有點煩  暫時不適應
I'm not badmouthing it, all right? I'm just saying, it's an adjustment.
桑  你這神秘東方人  生意怎麼樣
Sun. How are things in the mysterious East?
- 很好  非常忙  - 沒有非法漲價吧
- Very good. Very busy. - No unjustified price increases?
不  沒有  沒有  從來沒有
No, no, no. Never.
很好  兩杯咖啡  一杯普通的  一杯淡的
Good. Two coffees, one regular, one light.
- 你太太還好嗎  - 她感冒了
- How's the wife? - She has the flu.
聽到我很難過
I'm sorry to hear that.
算我請客
On the house.
- 謝謝惠顧  - 得謝謝你  太客氣了
- Thank you. - Thank you. That's very sweet of you.
往前走  向右拐
Down there, make a right.
我們最喜歡的韓國人被人打劫了
Our favorite Korean is getting robbed right now.
你說真的嗎
You serious?
首先  他說他老婆感冒了
First he tells me his wife has the flu.
噢  老兄  這個瘋婆娘除非死了她才不工作
Oh, man, that bitch would work if she was dead.
- 然後  他給了我咖啡卻沒有收錢  - 見鬼  他被打劫了  我們怎麼辦
- Then he gives me coffee for free. - Shit. He is getting robbed. How do we play it?
站得遠點  讓他們可以看到你  我從地下室進去
Stay out front so they can see you. I'll go through the basement.
- 別逞能  - 放心  請求增援
- Don't be a hero. - Don't worry. Call for some back-up.
快點
Faster.
Faster!
- 都站著別動  - 快拿過來
- Nobody moves. - Come on!
拿盒維吉尼亞香煙來
A carton of Virginia Slims.
那個警察就在外面
That cop's just sitting out there.
別管那警察
Don't worry about the cop.
什麼聲音
What was that?
到這兒來  注意警察
Come here. Watch him.
走吧  該走了  快點  夥計  走啊
Come on, let's go. Come on, pal. Move.
- 後面是什麼聲音  - 沒什麼  沒入口
- What's back through there? - Nothing. No entrance.
- 那門怎麼回事兒  - 是空的  是地下室  只有老鼠
- What about that door? - Empty. Basement. Just rats.
- 老鼠  - 大老鼠
- Rats? -Big ones.
我最討厭老鼠   為什麼不清理乾淨
I hate rats. Don't you keep this place clean?
誰都別動  不許動
Nobody move. Nobody!
那警察在幹嘛
What's with this cop?
他什麼都不會  只會開罰單
He's got nothing better to do than write tickets?
哪管得了紐約這麼多犯罪
With all the crime in this city?
- 我們怎麼辦  - 等到他離開
- What do we do? - Wait till he leaves.
- 如果他不走的話  又怎麼辦  - 他會走的  閉嘴
- What if he doesn't leave, then what? - He'll leave. Just shut up.
老婆  老婆  你怎麼啦
Honey, you all right?
- 她怎麼回事  - 她大概是犯心臟病了
- What's the matter with her? - I think she's having a heart attack.
- 閉嘴  - 快叫醫生
- Shut up. - Call a doctor.
在這兒我就是醫生
I'm the doctor here, honey.
見鬼
Shit.
起來  起來  查理  起來  老兄你沒事吧
Come on. Get up, Charlie. Get up, man. You all right?
進去  裏面  還有個傢伙在裏面
Get inside, inside, there's another one inside.
進去  還有個傢伙在裏面
Get in. There's another one inside.
起來  查理  起來  老兄  你還行嗎  老兄
Come on, Charlie, get up, man. You all right, man?
- 你幹嘛不對這個混蛋開槍啊  - 店裏面人太多了
- Why didn't you just shoot this asshole? - Too many customers.
- 你還好嗎  老兄  - 我還好
- You all right, man? - Yeah, I'm great.
噢  老兄  你中槍了
Oh, man, you got shot.
「彩票警察勇鬥劫犯」
他英勇地行為挽救了生命  並且防止更多無辜人員受傷  除了他自己
His heroism saved lives and prevented injuries, though not to himself.
他堅決的制止了犯罪份子
And certainly not to the criminals he stopped.
所以  我現在授予查理·蘭警官英勇獎章
So I give to Officer Charles Lang this citation for bravery...
並且祝他盡快康復  警官
...and wish him a quick recovery. Officer.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
我想這顆子彈告訴我  可以放鬆一段時間了  這是命運
I guess this bullet was fate telling me to take it easy for a while.
這是我太太說的
At least, that's what my wife says.
我喜歡做警察  不論怎樣
I love being a cop, lottery or no lottery.
我認為這是世上最重要的工作
I think it's the most important job in the world.
所以我決定給警察遺屬撫恤基金會
So I'd like to announce that I'll be donating $10,000...
捐贈一萬美元
...to the Policemen's Widows' Fund.
非常感謝
Thanks a lot.
查理  你很年輕  可不能像老頭兒一樣  賴在這兒閒逛
Charlie, you're too young to be hanging around here like an old man.
喂  我受傷了  你沒看報紙嗎  關於英雄警察的
Hey, I'm injured. Don't you read the papers? Hero cop?
- 像你這樣的英雄  一隻手也能玩球  - 如果可以的話  我也想試試
- If you're such a hero, play ball with one hand. - If I could, I would.
- 再見  - 嗯  一會兒見
- See you. - Yeah, see you later.
- 下午好  先生  - 下午好
- Good afternoon, sir. - Good afternoon.
- 這兒看起來像貝魯特似的  - 不錯吧
- This looks like Beirut. - Isn't it great?
噢  老公
Oh, honey.
這裏明年就要開發了  到時候我們將有六個房間的公寓賣出去
The building's going co-op next year, then we'll have a six-room apartment to sell.
- 帕特爾先生告訴我的  - 誰
- Mr. Patel told me. - Who?
帕特爾先生  我是你的會計師  你好  很高興見到你
Mr. Patel. Hi, I'm your accountant. Hello, pleased to meet you.
順便說說  正常情況下你們的未來前景非常好
By the way, all the very best on your new fortune.
謝謝
Thank you.
他說  這套公寓我們可能淨賺十萬美元
He says that we can make $100,000, pure profit, on this apartment.
保守估計
Minimum.
如果我們一年內搬到新澤西  那就連稅務都免了
And then we'll beat the state and city taxes if we move to Jersey within the year.
- 等等  我不想去新澤西  我想待在這裏  - 留下來幹嘛  打棒球啊
- But I don't wanna live in Jersey. I wanna stay here. - And do what? Play stickball?
建築師打來的  抱歉
It's the architect. Excuse me.
- 我的椅子在哪兒  - 我把它捐了
- Where's my chair? - I gave it to Goodwill.
你知道我很喜歡它  連問都不問我
But you know I love that chair. You could have asked me.
為什麼要問  反正你喜歡到處施捨
Why should I? You're the one that loves to give everything away.
女人  誰能和她們一起生活  誰又能沒有她們
Women. Who can live with them? And without them?
什麼
What?
- 格雷的古董店又被盜了 - 又被盜了嗎
- Gray's Antiques had another break-in. - Again?
是啊  倆兄弟溜進去偷了一件比德邁盔甲
Yeah. Two brothers walked off with a Biedermeier chest.
格雷說  黑人怎麼可能瞭解它的價值呢
Then Gray says to me, "How could some black guys know how much this is worth?"
- 不會吧  他這樣說的嗎  - 是啊  當著我的面說的
- Oh, come on. He said that? - Yeah. To me.
那你怎麼說的
What did you say?
我說  我想他們大概會向美國非洲古董協會咨詢
I said, "I guess they subscribe to the African-American Antiques Newsletter."
他很生我的氣
He pissed me off.
- 我挺想你的  夥計  - 我現在腦子一片空白
- I miss you, man. - I'm going out of my mind.
這生活就像地獄似的
This is like hell.
我的房子在裝修  沒我什麼事
My house is a wreck, and I got nothing to do....
其實  這就是退休生活
Well, that's retirement.
- 噢  伊芳餐館  - 她幾個星期前買下的
- Well. "Yvonne's." - She bought it a couple of weeks ago.
對她來說不錯
Good for her.
- 還需要些什麼  - 茶  謝謝
- Can I get you anything else? - Tea, please.
好的
Okay.
- 八號桌要杯茶  - 好的
- Eight wants tea. - Okay.
- 湯怎麼樣  - 不怎麼樣
- How's the soup? - Not enough basil.
你開玩笑吧  我看看能做些什麼
You're kidding me. I'll see what I can do.
- 進去吧  打個招呼  - 算了  她挺忙的
- Go in. Say hello. - Forget it, she's busy.
得了  夥計  我知道你想進去
Come on, man. I know you're dying to go in there.
不  我得回家  對了  我給你帶了樣東西
No, I've got to get home. By the way, I got you something.
- 紐約尼克斯隊的賽季套票  - 噢  天吶
- Season tickets to the Knicks. - Oh, shit!
- 不是最前排的  - 尼克斯隊的  老兄  給我的嗎
- They're not on the floor-- - Knicks tickets, man? For me?
你得是大人物才能坐在前排
You gotta be really somebody to get them on the floor.
沒關係  擁抱一下
Don't worry about that, give me some.
- 我該回家了  - 尼克斯隊的票
- I gotta go home. - Knicks tickets.
- 老兄  夠朋友  七號座  - 看到她很好  我也很高興
- Man, oh, man. Seat 7. - I'm glad she's doing well.
我不懂你為什麼要帶大衣來  晚上挺暖和的
I don't know why you had to bring this coat. It's a warm night.
也許過一會兒我會冷  拿好吧
Maybe I'll get a chill later. Just hold it.
- 這裏人真多啊  - 不錯吧
- There certainly are a lot of people here. - Isn't it great?
感覺就像參加奧斯卡頒獎典禮
I feel like we're at the Academy Awards.
- 謝謝  - 我去轉一轉
- Thank you. - I'm going to go circulate.
好的  寶貝兒
Okay, sweetheart.
- 這是你的唇膏  - 噢  謝謝
- Here's your lipstick. - Oh, thanks.
我賺了五千五百萬美元  並且讓我的淨資產增加了百分之四十
I won $55 million, and increased my net worth by 40 percent...
因為我選對了共有基金
...through a variety of well-chosen mutual funds.
- 百分之四十  - 幾乎沒有風險
- Forty percent? - At virtually no risk.
S & L基金  生物工程基金  黃金基金  它們都是垃圾
S & L funds, Biotech funds. Gold funds, they were a disaster.
離這些遠一點
Stay away from those.
噢  我會的  你認為國庫券怎麼樣
Oh, I will. What do you think about Treasury Bills?
呃  它們是給小老太太玩的  你顯然不是
Well, they're for little old ladies. Which you certainly are not.
你可真是頭猛獸
Aren't you a tiger.
為什麼你不能找開二十美元
How can you not have change for 20 dollars?
不可能啊  你整天都在開車
It's just not possible. You drive all day.
- 我們去找人換零錢  - 不  我們不能去找人換零錢
- We go get change. - No, we cannot go get change.
那你得換開
You have to break this.
嗨
Hi.
噢  你好  你好  你能找開二十塊零錢嗎
Well, hi. Hi. Can you break a 20?
你應該說  零錢不用找了
Repeat after me: "Keep the change."
- 零錢不用找了  - 謝謝
- "Keep the change." - Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 噢  我的上帝  船開了 - 噢  不  等等
- Oh my God, the boat. - Oh, no. Wait.
等等
Wait!
我想你太太是在
I suppose your wife is....
她跟她那一夥人在一起  股票經紀人  會計師  她喜歡和這些人在一起
She's in her element. Stockbrokers, CPAs, she'll probably have the time of her life.
- 你怎麼辦呢  - 我不喜歡船
- What about you? - I hate boats.
其實  這下正好  我可以不去了
You wanna know the truth? I'm relieved.
- 我想這是條鱘魚  - 顯然不是
- I think this is sturgeon. - This is definitely not sturgeon.
- 這就像天鵝絨  - 蘇格蘭三文魚  上等貨色
- It's just like velvet. - Scottish salmon. The very best.
再來點香檳
More champagne?
- 產自自命不凡的加利福尼亞  不錯哦  - 你不是開玩笑吧  加利福尼亞
- For pretentious California, it's not half bad. - You're not kidding. California?
愚弄我吧
Could have fooled me.
- 噢  上帝  這才是生活  - 這才剛剛開始
- Oh, God. This is living. - And it's just beginning.
- 你能再說一遍嗎  - 這才剛剛開始
- You can say that again. - And it's just beginning.
感覺真好
Very good.
謝謝你
Thank you.
為您服務非常榮幸  要雞尾酒  還是香檳  或者
It's a pleasure to have you here. Can I get you a cocktail? Or some champagne, perhaps?
- 香檳好嗎  香檳  - 很好
- Champagne? Champagne. - Very good.
- 謝謝  - 謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- 所以你決定不再做女演員了  - 是啊  我決定做女招待
- You decided not to become an actress? - Yeah. I decided to become a waitress.
我選擇了正確的女性職業
I had the "tress" part right.
- 我是個相當好的女招待 - 是啊  你做得很好
- And I was a great waitress. - The "tress" part.
我看到你買了那個地方
I saw you bought the place.
你看到了
You saw?
- 有一天我從門口經過  - 那你怎麼不進來
- I passed by the other day. - And you didn't come in?
呃  我  我不知道  我只是  我想你肯定很忙
Well, I.... I don't know, I just.... I figured you were busy.
你呀  你真應該進來  看看我怎麼做的
Please, you have to come in, you have to. You have to see what I did.
我還弄了一張以你的名字命名的飯桌  免費招待那些沒有錢的人
I established a table with your name on it, for people who couldn't afford a meal.
是嗎
No.
當然  在你做了那些事情之後  當然是的
Of course. After what you did. Of course.
我做什麼了  我只是履行了諾言  我一直都這樣
What I did? I made a promise and I kept it, period.
大多數人都會這樣做
Most people would've done the same.
沒有人會這樣做
Nobody would've done the same.
你開玩笑呢  你所做的就像是一個童話
Are you kidding? What you did was like a fairy tale.
然後每個人都幸福快樂地生活著
And everyone gets to live happily ever after?
- 噢  這真是幸福的一對  - 你這麼看嗎
- Well, that's a hopeful sight. - You think?
我不知道
I don't know.
我總是想知道  他們準備好了嗎
I always wonder, what's in store for them?
他們會得到幸福嗎
Are they gonna be happy?
我的意思是  假如她胖上五十磅  他還會愛她嗎
I mean, if she puts on 50 pounds or something, will he love her anyway?
- 你結婚幾年了  - 三年了
- How long were you married? - Three years.
嫁了一個叫艾迪的演員
To an actor named Eddie.
他還提議如果我們有了孩子  就取名叫艾爾·帕西諾
Who suggested that if we had a child, we name him Al Pacino.
- 艾爾·帕西諾·比亞西  - 別逗了
- Al Pacino Biasi. - Come on.
我也這麼想
That's what I said.
穆麗兒和我是在高中的時候認識的  在一堂烹飪課上
Muriel and I met in high school, in one of those cooking classes...
在那所有人都穿得像廚子
...where all the guys dress up like Chef Boyardee.
每分鐘  都像是消防演習
And you figure any minute, there's gonna be a fire drill.
然後你就穿著圍裙逃到外面啦
And you're all outside in your aprons?
沒錯  直到現在  想起來都會打哆嗦
Exactly. Even now, thinking about it, I get chills.
總之  後來我們開始約會  而且
Anyhow, we started dating, and....
穆麗兒是我的初戀
Muriel was the first girl I ever....
- 真的嗎  - 真的
- Really? - Yeah.
- 噢  真甜蜜  - 我想是的
- Well, that's sweet. - I guess.
然後我們就一起去了婚姻許可登記處  那裏還有其它情侶
We went down to the marriage-license bureau, and I remember, there was this other couple there.
他們是東正教猶太人  還是包辦婚姻
They were Orthodox Jews. It was an arranged marriage.
包辦婚姻
An arranged marriage?
之前夫妻雙方都不准見面  他們都被親人圍著
They weren't allowed to see each other. They were surrounded by their families.
連互相瞥一眼都不可能
They couldn't get a glimpse of each other.
我就想  我的上帝  他們甚至不知道自己是否吸引對方
And I remember thinking, "My God. They don't even know if they're attracted to each other.
他們甚至不知道是否有共同的話題
They don't even know if they've got anything to talk about with each other."
然後  十年過去了  我敢打賭  他們現在有六個可愛的小孩  幸福地生活在一起
And here it is, ten years later, and I bet they're happily married with six cute little kids.
但是穆麗兒和我  現在沒話可說了  我不知道怎麼了
But Muriel and I have nothing to say to one another. I don't know what happened.
就像我們是兩個不同的頻道  我是CNN新聞頻道  她是家庭購物頻道
It's like we're on two different channels now. I'm CNN, she's the Home Shopping Network.
我們跳一曲  怎麼樣
How would you feel about dancing?
噢  我很樂意
Oh, I'd be in favor of it.
我還是個新手的時候常值夜班  那時候  我感覺像在探險
When I was a rookie, I had the night shift, and I felt like an explorer.
整個紐約  是座不夜城
Because there's this whole other city that goes on all night long.
- 我是不是有點兒嘮叨  - 是啊
- Am I talking incessantly? - Yes.
但我喜歡  我自己就比較嘮叨
But I like it. I myself am a talker.
所以  沒什麼
So, I don't know.
我喜歡跟那些談得來的人一起聊聊天散散步
It's nice to meet somebody who you can just talk with, you know, and hang with.
你瞧  這剛好  我現在基本上每天都閒著
Look, here's the thing. I'm free all the time, basically.
所以  如果你想做點什麼或是想聊天的話
So if there's anything you ever wanna do during the day...
- 或是你獨自一人什麼也不想幹的時候  - 真的嗎
- ...or you're alone and you don't wanna be.... - Really?
- 當然  - 明天怎麼樣
- Sure. - How about tomorrow?
明天
Tomorrow?
- 太快了嗎  - 不  一點也不
- Too soon? - No, not at all.
好  太棒了  好吧  我讓卡洛兒看著店
Okay, great. Okay. So, I'll have Carol watch the register...
中午你就來接我  行嗎
...and you could come by, pick me up at noon?
我會來的
I'll be there.
- 好啊  - 那就說定了
- Okay. - All right.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 晚安  - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
嗨  不可思議  我以為錢包掉在外面了
Hi. Weirdest thing happened. I thought I'd dropped my wallet outside.
不可思議  我覺得有點暈船就到外面來了
Weirdest thing happened. I came outside because I was feeling a little seasick.
真是不可思議
Weirdest thing happened.
我有一些好點子
I have some wonderful ideas.
- 如果你真想  - 嗨
- Specifically with you in mind. - Hi.
真是奇怪了
Weirdest thing happened.
牛肉怎麼樣
Wasn't the veal fabulous?
好極了  真奇怪  我不怎麼喜歡牛肉  我更喜歡雞肉
Fabulous. That was what was so weird. I didn't expect veal. I expected chicken.
我本來是要找你的  但格羅斯先生在這裏
I would have come sit with you, but Mr. Gross here....
- 傑克·格羅斯  - 很高興認識你
- Jack Gross. - My pleasure.
很高興認識你  警官
Pleased to meet you, officer.
查理  他說要幫我們賺錢
Charlie, he's going to help us develop an economic strategy.
- 好主意  - 是你太太提出的  警官  她很聰明
- What a great idea. - You have some girl here, officer. Smart.
而且漂亮  她知道自己想要的東西
Beautiful. And she knows what she wants.
- 看到了吧  - 我同意
- See? - I agree.
非常感謝你  今晚你令我大開眼界  格羅斯先生
Thank you very much for a very stimulating evening, Mr. Gross.
這是我的榮幸
My pleasure.
- 如果你需要什麼建議  無論你  - 我會打給你的
- If you ever need any advice, either of you.... - I will be calling.
- 好嗎  - 當然
- Well, ready? - Sure.
走吧  我們上樓去拿我的大衣
Come on, let's get upstairs. I gotta get my coat.
- 再見  - 再見
- Bye-bye. - Bye-bye.
噢  不行
Oh, no.
- 你做得不錯  - 我從來掌握不好平衡
- You're doing great. - I never had great balance.
我試過滑雪  結果從皮特兔子斜坡上摔了下來
I tried skiing once. They threw me off the Peter Rabbit slope.
- 注意彎曲膝蓋  問題就在這兒  - 這只是其中一個毛病
- You gotta bend your knees. That's your problem. - That's one of them.
小心  這裏有個小坡  你要注意  別
So now, there's a little bit of a hill here, so you might want to watch it, so don't--
- 減速  - 我慢不下來
- Slow down. - I can't slow down.
- 你行的  - 我行的  我不行
- Sure you can. - Sure I can-- I can't.
- 查理  轉彎  - 我知道
- Charlie, turn. - Okay.
- 你還好吧  - 很好
- Are you okay? - Fine.
我也許會因為浸水而得上麻風病  不過  此外就沒事了
I mean, I'll probably catch leprosy from the water, but otherwise I'm okay.
我想你是再也不想溜旱冰了
So I guess this is it for you and rollerblading?
我剛想說來著
I would have to say yes.
好了  輪到你了  下面你打算幹嘛
Okay, your turn. What next? What do you want to do?
女士們先生們  我是查理·蘭  我買彩票中了獎
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm Charlie Lang, and I've just won the lottery.
今晚乘車  由我和伊芳·比亞西小姐  為大家買票
Tonight's ride home is on me and Miss Yvonne Biasi.
- 出什麼事了  - 警察和女招待請大家免費乘車
- What's going on? - The cop and the waitress are treating everybody.
- 沒有比這更好的事了  - 我能想到更好的
-This is going to be hard to top. - I'll top it.
現在的時間是下午五點十六分  感謝您搭乘紐約交通管理局地鐵
The time is now 5:16 p.m. Thank you for riding with the New York Transit Authority.
歡迎查理·蘭  伊芳·比亞西
Welcome to Charlie Lang, Yvonne Biasi...
鮑·威廉姆斯警官
...Officer Bo Williams...
和每一個來自皇后區附近的小朋友們
...and all the kids from Woodside, Queens.
我知道  我知道  我再試試
I know, I know. I'm trying.
衝過去
Out of there!
三壘
Third base!
達陣
Out of there!
好球
Good one.
- 跳  - 對啦
- Go. - All right.
- 好了  - 查理  查理  查理  查理
- Come on. - Charlie, Charlie, Charlie.
好了  好了  嗨  嗨
Okay. Well, hey. Hey!
今天真棒  對我來說也是
It was a great day. It was a great day for me too.
- 她這是在幹什麼  - 她生氣了  她什麼都不顧了
- What the hell is she doing? - She's pissed, whatever she's doing.
穆麗兒
Muriel.
Muriel!
- 祝賀你  車票先生  - 噢  上帝
- Congratulations, Mr. Token Man. - Oh, God.
「樂透彩票羅賓漢」
- 親愛的  我回來了 - 不行  不行  你給我出去
- Honey, I'm home. - No. No, you have to leave.
這個太好吃了
These are fantastic.
- 不許吃我的澳洲胡桃仁  - 吻我一下
- Stop eating my macadamia nuts. - Give me a kiss.
不  不  我是認真的  我可是認真的
No. No, I'm serious, I'm serious.
- 你給我出去  滾出去  - 為什麼  你在等情人嗎
- You can't stay here. Out. - Why? You expecting company?
- 沒有  沒有 - 不會吧
- No. No. - No?
不會是那個高尚的聖人警察吧
Not Officer Krupke, the saintly cop?
我和他之間什麼也沒有發生  而且他也不是什麼聖人
There's nothing going on between me and Charlie Lang. And he's not a saint...
他只是一個普通的體面人  你這種人一輩子也不可能做到
...he's just simply a decent human being. Something you couldn't possibly--
如果你再吃一個  我發誓
If you eat one more of those nuts, I swear to you....
- 你跟這個姑娘在搞婚外情嗎  - 沒有  當然沒有  我們只是一起出去
- Are you having an affair with this girl? - No, of course not. We just hang out together.
你真應該聽聽樓下那個俄羅斯婆子說的  你丈夫和女招待如何如何
You should've heard that Russian bitch downstairs, "Oh, your husband and that waitress."
但是  好了  我們到底在這爭論什麼
But, okay, what's the real issue here?
我們之間是怎麼回事  樓下那些傻瓜鄰居又與我們何干
What's happening between us, or what some idiot neighbor thinks?
這裏就像冷戰似的  每當我想跟你談談  你總是
It's been like a cold war here. And every time I've tried to talk about it, you--
- 我所做的只是想讓你開心  - 不  你根本沒有那樣做
- All I have done is tried to make you happy. - No, that's not all you've tried to do.
以前我晚上回來  你總是跑過來擁抱我
I used to come home at night, and you'd throw your arms around me.
你吻我  還問我今天過得怎樣  你上次這樣做是什麼時候？
You'd kiss me and say, "How was your day?" When's the last time that happened?
五年前嗎
Five years ago?
- 我想不起來了  這不重要  - 不  這很重要
- I have no idea. It's not important. - No, but it is important.
已經成為歷史了
It's history.
- 你現在圍著那個女孩轉  - 我沒有和她搞婚外情
- You go around with this girl. - I'm not having an affair.
你跟那個警察的事  坦率地說我並不關心
This thing between you and the cop, frankly, it's none of my business.
但是有一件非常重要的事情  那就是
But there is one thing that's very important, and it's this.
別害怕
Don't be afraid.
艾迪·比亞西賭場
"The Eddie Biasi Players."
你想要錢  當然了  你是想要錢
You want money. Of course you want money.
僅僅只要五萬塊  然後我們就互不相干
Just 50 grand in seed money. And then we're off and running.
好吧  寶貝兒  看  在這兒  簽字吧
Okay, honey, look. Picture this, picture this. Please, please.
當然沒有  你沒有  聖人先生沒有  你太神聖了  不會發生婚外情
Of course not. Not you, not Mr. Saintly. You're too good to have an affair.
噢  上帝  查理  我受夠了你所謂的正派禮儀
Oh, God, Charlie. I'm just so sick of it. Your niceness and your decency.
但是你知道你是什麼嗎
But you wanna know what?
你什麼都不是  你只是個會打工的笨蛋  一輩子都是藍領
You're nothing. You're a working-class stiff. You are blue collar all the way.
我不想改變  穆麗兒
I'm not gonna change, Muriel.
我知道
I know.
- 所以  我要離婚  - 你想離婚
- So I want a divorce. - You want a divorce?
越快越好
As soon as possible.
我的翅膀硬了  查理  我要單飛
I have wings, Charlie. I want to fly.
甜心  甜心
Honey? Honey?
好吧  你看  底線是  我就粘在這兒
All right, look, babe, the bottom line is, I'm sticking around--
直到你同意
Which I have a right to do. --until you kick in.
你粘在這兒吧  我走  我不想再看到你
Well, you stick around, because I am out of here.
- 你要去哪兒  大人物  - 讓開
- Where are you going, big shot? - Get away from that door.
你要去哪兒  廣場酒店嗎
Where are you going? The Plaza?
-  沒錯  廣場酒店  - 當真
-Yeah, the Plaza. - Really?
當然是真的  我回來的時候如果你還在這裏  我就報警
Really. And if you're still here when I get back, I'm calling the cops.
相信我  現在我有這個資格讓他們來
And believe me, I am now in a position to get them to come.
- 你去哪兒  - 旅館
- Where you going? - A hotel.
- 你的意思是  你和她  - 我們完了
- You mean, you and her? - We're history.
- 不能說我很驚訝  - 沒關係  我很可笑吧  我是很可笑
- Can't say I'm surprised. - No? It's funny, I am.
不管以前發生過什麼  只是不希望會這樣
No matter what comes before, you just don't expect this.
- 哪個旅館  查理  如果我要找你呢  - 第九大道的假日旅社
- What hotel, Charlie? What if I wanna call you? - I'll be at the Holiday Inn on Ninth.
- 假日旅社  - 是啊
- Holiday Inn? - Yeah.
- 查理  拜託  你中了頭彩哎  - 那又怎樣
- Charlie, you won the lottery. - Yeah?
你起碼去廣場酒店待一晚上吧
One night at least, stay at the Plaza.
也許我會的  你可真夠哥們  知道嗎
Maybe I will. You're a real pal, you know that?
我會來看你們
I'll see you guys.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
- 我想要一個房間  - 好的  女士
- I'd like to get a room. - Yes, ma'am.
我不是那個女招待  如果你那麼想的話
I'm not that waitress, if that's what you're thinking.
我沒有那麼想
I didn't think so.
- 單人間還是雙人間  - 單人
- Single or double? - A single.
- 吸煙不吸煙  - 不吸煙
- Smoking or non-smoking? - Non-smoking.
先生  需要我幫忙嗎
Sir, can I help you?
- 他搬回來了  - 她把我趕出來了
- He moved back in. - She threw me out.
8-11號房從這邊走  女士
Eight-11 is this way, ma'am.
先生  請您跟我來
Sir? If you'll just follow me.
- 他就是那個警察吧  - 還有那個女招待
- That was the cop. - That's the waitress.
看過你的盥洗室了沒有  那兒準備了浴袍
Checked your bathroom yet? There's a robe in it.
- 真的嗎  - 對天發誓
- Are you serious? - Swear to God.
- 呃  晚安  - 請進來吧
- Well, good night. - Come in.
請進
Come in.
謝謝
Thanks.
難以置信  你的房間和我的一模一樣  就顏色有點不同
Unbelievable. Your room is exactly like mine, exactly like mine, except it's a different color.
他們真的  我的意思是
They really.... I mean....
想吃點水果嗎
Hey, would you like some fruit?
你的房間也有  這家酒店的每間客房應該都有水果
You have some in your.... Every room in this hotel probably has fruit.
真是太棒了
It's amazing.
- 那兒真的有浴袍嗎  - 還是棉布的
- There's really a robe in there? - Terry cloth.
相當不錯
Nice. Really nice.
是賣的  你可以花一百塊錢買一件  我想是一百塊錢
It's for sale. You can buy it for like $100 or something. I think it's $100, yeah.
我會買一件
I'll do it.
那我出一半的錢吧  這樣我們就可以合著用它
I'll split it with you. That way we can share it.
你用一個月  我用一個月
You can have it one month, and I'll take it one month.
或者每天換一次  或者每周換一次
Or every other day, or weekends.
- 或者我們買兩件  - 我們可以
- Or we could get two. - We could do that.
- 我怎麼會這麼緊張呢  - 我不知道
- Why am I so nervous? - I don't know.
- 我們認識很長時間了  - 也許就是因為這個
- We've spent so much time together. - Maybe that's why.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
我們走吧
Here we go.
他們在那兒
There they are.
- 真不敢相信  - 放鬆點  先生們
- This is unbelievable. - Make yourselves comfortable, gentlemen.
- 我見過許多大辦公室  - 沃爾特  拜託
- I mean, I've seen some offices. - Walter, please.
天吶  這種地方肯定收費不菲
Boy, these guys must charge you an arm and a leg.
你幹嘛不坐下
Why don't you sit down?
看看這椅子  查理
Just the chairs, Charlie.
- 你要來杯水嗎  - 我想一定是真皮的
- Would you like a glass of water? - Real leather. I thought so.
- 穆麗兒在哪兒  - 蘭太太剛出來
- Where's Muriel? - Mrs. Lang just stepped out.
她來了
And here she is.
- 你果然那樣做了  - 做什麼了
- You had them done. - Had what done?
- 可以開始了嗎  - 什麼  她做什麼了
- Can we proceed please? - What did she have done?
有什麼好神秘的
What's the mystery?
- 我一會兒告訴你  - 我是你的律師
- I'll tell you later. - I'm your lawyer.
就像人們在好萊塢說的一樣  讓我們結束這段故事吧
As they say in Hollywood, let's cut to the chase.
彩票獎金  我們認為不應該分
It is our contention that there be no division of the lottery money.
因為這是蘭太太的彩票
This was Mrs. Lang's ticket.
- 這是完全不能接受的  - 我接受
- That's completely unacceptable. - It's all right.
- 她可以拿走我的那一半  - 什麼
- She can have my half. - What?
過來
Come here.
你是傻子嗎  你為什麼不爭取就放棄
Are you nuts? Why are you giving this away without a fight?
她拿走我那一半好了  就這樣吧  我不想再討論這個問題
She can have my half, period. I don't wanna discuss it.
不想討論這個問題  你所說的是一百萬美元啊
Don't wanna discuss it? You're talking a million dollars.
沃爾特  行了
Walter, please.
你在跟我開玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
- 在這一點上我們讓步  - 這是非常成熟慎重的態度
- We concede the point. - That's a very mature attitude.
這肯定會讓問題盡快正確解決
It'll certainly help speed things right along.
那麼  現在  關於他們中彩前的財產
Well, now, as to their pre-lottery holdings...
這裏有份銀行賬戶清單
...we have a bank account here totaling...
一共有三千六百一十一美元  我建議對半分
...$3611. I insist we split this 50-50.
傻瓜開竅了啊
Chump change.
好  基本就是這樣  還有一些傢俱 一些亞麻布被單
Well, that's basically it. There's furnishings, some good linens.
這些不太重要  查庫圖先生
Not quite accurate, Mr. Zakuto.
我們要討論一下  蘭先生分給比亞西小姐的款項
We are also attaching the monies given by Mr. Lang to Miss Biasi.
- 什麼  不行  - 這太過分了
- What? No. - That is out of bounds.
蘭先生未經妻子同意
Mr. Lang volunteered his wife's earnings from the lottery...
擅自處理蘭太太的彩票所得
...without her consent or previous knowledge.
這太過分了  穆麗兒  看在上帝的份上  想想你在做什麼
That's horrible, Muriel. For God's sake. Please, think about what you're doing.
我們有理由相信  他和比亞西小姐
We have every reason to believe that he and Miss Biasi...
有著長期的情人關係
...have had a long-standing relationship...
然後他故意欺騙了他的妻子
...that he deliberately deceived his wife about.
為此
And toward that end...
- 我們已經起草了針對比亞西小姐的訴訟單  - 卑鄙
- ...we have drafted this letter to Miss Biasi... - Come on!
要求她歸還這筆錢
...demanding that she return the money...
立即全部歸還  否則將面臨巨額賠償和罰款
...immediately and in full, or face substantial penalties and damages.
- 簡直難以置信  - 我無法再忍受他大叫大鬧了
- I can't believe this. - I can't listen to this screaming.
- 我們的婚姻一直這樣  - 事實並不是這樣
- Our whole marriage was like this. - It was not like this!
你為什麼要這樣做
Why are you doing this?
你想從伊芳那裏得到什麼  她沒做錯任何事
Just to get even with Yvonne? She didn't do anything wrong.
我已經對你的虐待感到麻木了  你們看見了嗎
I am tired of this physical abuse from you. Did you see that?
如果你們要一輛出租車  我的秘書會幫你們
If you fellows need a cab, my secretary will call one.
我應該怎麼和伊芳說呢  我該怎麼告訴她呢
How am I going to say this to Yvonne? How am I gonna tell her?
查理  這樣不行  這段時間你必須停止和她見面
Charlie, you're not gonna like this, but you're gonna have to stop seeing her for a while.
嗨  我是伊芳·比亞西  現在不在家
Hi. This is Yvonne Biasi. I'm not at home right now.
請在嗶聲後留言  非常感謝
Please leave a message after the beep. Thanks so much.
伊芳  我只想說我很擔心你
Yvonne, I just wanted to say I'm thinking about you.
我們會贏的  因為我們是對的  別認為這是你的錯  根本不是
And we're gonna win this thing, because it's right. Don't think any of this is your fault. It isn't.
我在鮑的家裏  有事就打555-3840  看來我只能在法庭上再見到你了
If you need me, I'll be at Bo's, 555-3840. I guess I'll see you in court.
希望你不介意睡在地板上
Well, I hope you don't mind sleeping on the floor.
噢  當然不會  謝謝
Oh, no, thank you.
冰箱裏有啤酒  電視機在那裏
There's beer in the fridge, and the TV's there.
特蕾西  謝謝你讓我用你的毛毯
Sure is nice of you to let me use your Barney blanket, Tracey.
這沒關係
That's okay.
- 晚安  - 晚安  蓋爾  我很抱歉
- Good night. - Good night, Gail. I'm sorry.
別擔心  哥們
Don't worry about it, man.
謝謝
Thanks.
這個轟動全城的訴訟
"The trial, which has attracted citywide interest...
將於今天上午九點半在民事法庭開庭審理
...begins in civil court this morning at 9:30."
- 整件事情都太離奇了  - 我相信錢會歸伊芳
- This whole thing is unbelievable. - My money's on Yvonne.
上帝  我也希望如此
God, I hope so.
蘭太太  請問你的生日是哪天
Now, Mrs. Lang, what are the numbers for your birthday?
64年12月16日
Twelve, 16, 64.
那麼結婚紀念日呢  親愛的
And the numbers for your anniversary, my dear?
84年6月26日
Six, 26, 84.
6月26日
Six, 26....
我聽到的是26嗎
Did I hear 26?
二十六嗎
Twenty-six?
而事實上  蘭太太  你不是27號結婚的嗎
As a matter of fact, Mrs. Lang, weren't you married on the 27th?
- 是的  - 所以  是你丈夫自己選擇的26
- Yes. - So your husband picked the 26 on his own?
- 反對  這問題有什麼意義  - 關鍵在於  辯護律師
- Objection. What's the point? - The point is, counselor...
重點是  法官大人  我將證明
...the point is, Your Honor, I am demonstrating...
是因為蘭先生的選擇  彩票才中了獎
...that Mr. Lang is responsible for the winning ticket.
反對無效
Overruled.
那麼  蘭太太  是你的丈夫自己選擇了屬於他的26號  對嗎
So, Mrs. Lang, your husband picked the 26th on his own, correct?
- 不對  - 不對嗎
- No. - No?
蘭太太  當時你和你丈夫在一起
Mrs. Lang, there was you, there was your husband.
你可以告訴我們  那天早上還有誰和你們在一起嗎
Could you kindly tell us who else was there that morning?
我死去的父親
My dead father.
- 抱歉 能說清楚些嗎  - 我死去的父親  上帝寬恕他的靈魂
- Excuse me? - My dead father, God rest his soul.
請肅靜
Quiet, please.
他進入我的夢裏  他邊說邊飄上窗口  寶貝兒
He came to me in a dream. "Baby," he says, as he was floating out the window.
他有一雙大翅膀  你知道  像天使一樣的翅膀
You know, he had these big wings, you know, like angel wings.
噢  我的上帝啊  穿著完美的白色長袍
Oh, my God. They were the perfect color of white leather.
他說  寶貝兒  該去教堂了
Anyway, he says, "Baby, it's time to go to the church.
你得快點  否則你就要遲到了
You gotta hurry up or you're gonna be late."
太讓我震驚了  那時我正穿著婚紗站在那兒
To my shock and surprise, I'm standing there in my wedding gown.
所以我跑過了皇后大街  穿過弗拉特布什大街
So I was running down Queen's Boulevard, through Flatbush.
跑過皇后大街  穿過了弗拉特布什大街之後
Even though Queen's Boulevard doesn't run through Flatbush.
我來到教堂  好來樂透的聖凱瑟琳教堂
I came to the church: St. Catherine's of the Holy Lotto.
我不但沒有遲到  還早到了整整一天
And then I realized I wasn't late, I was a whole day early.
天啊  我真該死
God, I wanted to die.
他在那裏  知道嗎  我父親就站在我邊上
Then my father, you know, he was there, he was standing right next to me.
他說  孩子  別哭
And he says, "Little girl, don't cry.
對我來說  你的結婚紀念日就是26號
Because to me, your anniversary will always be on the 26th."
「穆麗兒的先父托夢造就彩票贏家」
蘭先生
Mr. Lang.
你為你太太買過指甲油嗎
Have you ever purchased nail-polish remover for your wife?
肅靜
Quiet, please.
洗甲水呢
Nail-polish remover?
- 我想有幾次吧  - 你付錢買的嗎
- A couple of times, I guess. - And you paid for it?
- 當然  - 因此你就認為它們就是屬於你的啦
- Sure. - Did you therefore consider it yours?
不  我不這麼想
No, I guess I didn't.
你真的強迫過你太太與比亞西小姐平分獎金嗎
Isn't it true that you forced your wife to split the ticket with Miss Biasi?
我只是說  我們應該做正確的事
I only said we should do the right thing.
- 蘭先生  那時你帶著槍嗎  - 沒有  當然沒有
- Mr. Lang, were you wearing a gun at the time? - No. Of course not.
- 你打她了  是嗎  蘭先生  - 我沒有  從來沒有
- You hit her, didn't you, Mr. Lang? - I never, ever--
你可是宣過誓的  蘭先生
You are under oath, Mr. Lang.
- 好吧  有一次我抓住她的胳膊  - 沒有其它問題了
- Okay, once I grabbed her arm-- - No further questions.
「彩票警察毆打妻子」
你的證人  律師
Your witness, counselor.
比亞西小姐  請你描述一下
Miss Biasi. Would you describe your financial circumstances...
蘭先生分給你一半屬於他太太的獎金之前的財務狀況
...before Mr. Lang was kind enough to offer you half his wife's winning ticket?
我盡量努力  但還是入不敷出
I was struggling to make ends meet.
萬事達信用卡上還欠著一萬兩千美元是屬實的吧
Isn't it a fact you owed $12,000 on your MasterCard?
- 那是我前夫欠的  - 只需回答是或否
- That's because my ex-husband-- - Just answer yes or no.
理論上來說  是的  但我從來沒有透支過
Technically, yes. But that's not because I had overspent.
而且是在你破產的同一天
And isn't it also a fact that you filed for bankruptcy...
也是在這一天  蘭先生承諾會分給你一半獎金的吧
...on the very day Mr. Lang offered to split the ticket?
是的  不過  那只是巧合
Yes. But that was just fate.
- 是啊  巧合  - 是的  真的
- Right, fate. - Yes. Really.
我來問你  當蘭先生提出
Let me ask you, what was your relationship...
把妻子的獎金分給你一半的時候  你們之間是什麼關係
...with Mr. Lang at the time he offered to share his wife's ticket with you?
- 我從來沒有見過他  - 真的嗎
- I'd never met him before. - Really?
是真的
Yes, really.
描述一下現在你和蘭先生的關係
Describe your relationship with Mr. Lang today.
我愛他  勝過世間的一切
I love him more than anything in the world.
所以那天你去酒店和他會面
Which is why you went running off to the Plaza with him...
這也是他離開他太太的原因
...on the day he separated from his wife.
- 反對  這有什麼關係  - 動機
- Objection. What is the relevancy of this? - Motivation.
什麼動機
What motivation?
蘭太太把他趕出家門  婚姻走到盡頭了
Mrs. Lang had thrown Mr. Lang out of the house, the marriage was in complete disarray.
- 反對無效  - 如果你是暗示我是個
- Overruled. - If you're implying what I think--
比亞西小姐
Miss Biasi.
他們企圖把我說成是一個騙子  他  還有媒體
They're trying to make me into a gold digger. Him, the media.
比亞西小姐  請控制一下情緒
Miss Biasi. Control yourself, please.
我一直都在努力工作  終於意外地迎來異常奇妙的一刻
I've worked my whole life. And finally something wonderful happened to me.
我遇到了一個聰明  善良而且充滿愛心的男人
I met a man who was intelligent and kind and full of compassion.
認識他已經改變了我的生活  這絕不是錢的問題
Just the experience of knowing him has changed my life. It's not the money.
這是因為他使我  再次從根本上相信  人性依然是善良的
It's because he made me believe again people were fundamentally decent.
我不想讓什麼律師  歪曲我們的關係  醜化這份感情
I'll be damned if I'm gonna let some lawyer make our relationship look ugly.
你離婚了嗎
Are you divorced?
沒有
No.
就是說你和一個人結婚了  卻又愛上另一個
You're married to one man, and you're in love with another.
- 這只是因為我付不起離婚費用  - 好啊 這理由方便
- It's only because I couldn't afford to get divorced. - Well, that's convenient.
在戲劇性的證詞裏  伊芳·比亞西被穆麗兒的律師描述成
In dramatic testimony, Yvonne Biasi was depicted by Muriel Lang's attorney...
一個淫蕩的金錢詐騙犯  本案預計今天晚上作出裁決
...as a gold-digger and nymphomaniac. A verdict was expected by this evening.
- 陪審團作出裁決了嗎  - 是的  法官大人
- Has the jury reached a verdict? - We have, Your Honor.
宣讀吧
What say you?
我們一致認為  原告穆麗兒·蘭太太勝訴
We rule in favor of the plaintiff, Mrs. Muriel Lang, on all counts.
法庭對陪審團在這困難的情況下所作的努力表示感謝
The court would like to thank the jury for its service in this difficult case.
退庭
Court is dismissed.
- 關於你和伊芳的通姦  - 別再侮辱她
- About the reports of Yvonne's adultery-- - Shut up about her.
她在下面
She's down there.
伊芳
Yvonne!
- 蘭太太  你對裁決有什麼看法  - 非常公正
- Mrs. Lang? Your reaction to the verdict? - Justice was done.
難道你不認為你丈夫所做的是好事嗎
Don't you believe that the good deeds of your husband--?
這不是記者招待會  法庭的裁決很公正  我們很高興  就這樣
This is not a press conference. The verdict is in. We're happy, that's all.
非常滿意
Very happy.
「警察與女招待敗訴」
我都不知道她在哪裏
I don't even know where she is.
瞧  你還可以回來做警察  這是你喜歡的事
Look, you'll be a cop again. It's what you love.
我會沒事的
I'll be all right.
有人嗎
Hello?
有人在嗎
Is anyone here?
走吧
Go away.
伊芳
Yvonne.
- 不  你不會想再和我在一起的  - 你說什麼呢
- No. You don't wanna be with me. - What are you talking about?
- 我愛你  - 不  你還不明白嗎
- I love you. - No. Don't you get it?
我毀了你的生活
I've ruined your life.
你瘋了嗎  沒有你在的這些日子  我感覺自己像丟了魂似的
Are you crazy? These past couple of days, I felt like half of me was missing.
你中了四百萬美元啊  你知道這是多麼驚人的一份厚禮嗎
You won $4 million in the lottery. Do you know what an amazing gift that is?
而現在  因為我  你什麼都沒有了
And because of me you have nothing.
正是因為你  我愛你  難道你還不明白嗎
Because of you, I have you. Why can't you understand that?
如果你不想要我  這是另一回事
If you don't want me, that's different.
如果你不要我  我會走出這道門  你永遠都不會再見到我
If you don't want me, I'll walk right out that door, and you'll never see me again.
但是別再說什麼錢  錢對我沒有任何意義
But please stop talking about the money. It means nothing to me.
你希望我走嗎
Do you want me to go?
不
No.
永遠不
Never.
永遠別走  永遠
Never, never.
有些時候你該原諒我  因為
You have to excuse me sometimes, it's just...
從來沒有人這樣愛過我
...nobody ever loved me before.
- 我想他可能想找點吃的  - 我們讓他進來吧
- I guess he wants some food. - Shall we invite him in?
為什麼不呢
Why not?
我們應該離開紐約
We should leave New York.
我的意思是  我們在這裏都成怪物了
I mean, we're like freaks here.
我有個遠親住在水牛城
I've got a cousin that lives in Buffalo.
他一直叫我過去
He keeps asking me to visit.
也許我們可以在那兒呆上一陣子
Maybe we can stay there for a while.
我可以在水牛城當警察
I could join the Buffalo force.
我可以在水牛城做女招待
I could be a Buffalo waitress.
今晚  我  安吉爾·杜普裏  一個從業十年的紐約郵報攝影記者
Tonight I, Angel Dupree, a photographer for the New York Post for 10 years...
有機會在惡劣的天氣裏  感受到什麼是真正的樂善好施
...had the opportunity to study grace and generosity under the direst of circumstances.
「紐約郵報」
「黑暗時刻的溫情」
即使他們非常困難  這位勇敢的蘭警官和好心腸的比亞西小姐
Even in their darkest hour, the stalwart Officer Lang and the good-hearted Miss Biasi...
仍然讓我享受了一碗美味的熱湯
...shared a bowl of soup with me.
臨走時  這位好心人還從他口袋裏掏錢給我
When I left, this Good Samaritan gave me money from his own pocket...
還希望我別嫌少
...wishing it could be more.
- 請寄往摩爾北街  伊芳咖啡館  - 這是一個好主意
- "Mail it to Yvonne's Coffee Shop." - It's a good idea.
這個主意棒極了
It's a great idea.
我就看一眼
I just want to make one stop.
- 親愛的  - 我挺好  我挺好
- Sweetie. - I'm okay, I'm okay.
- 我看這樣不太好  - 沒關係  我只是想再看看
- I knew this was a bad idea. - No, I just wanted to see it again.
門怎麼開了
Why is the gate open?
我不知道  嗯  卡洛兒有鑰匙
I don't know. Well, Carol has a key.
門被頂住了
The door's stuck.
- 這是什麼  - 誰弄錯了吧
- What is this? - It must be some kind of a mistake.
- 好撒瑪利亞人關懷基金  - 彩票情侶
- "The Good Samaritan's Fund." - "Lotto Lovers."
寄給伊芳咖啡館
"Yvonne's Coffee Shop."
- 這兒有五美元  - 噢  怎麼回事  不對吧
- It's 5 dollars. - Oh, come on. No.
世上應該有越來越多像你們這樣的人  斯泰登島  艾瑟兒寄
"There should be more people in the world like you. Ethel from Staten Island."
這是一張十美元的支票
Here's a check for 10.
這些都是給我們的  噢  查理
This is all for us. Oh, Charlie.
「捐給查理和伊芳」
你們為大家樹立了好榜樣  布朗克斯區  貝蒂和菲爾
"You are an example to all of us. Betty and Phil, the Bronx."
我們希望你們擁有美好的未來  長島  加西亞一家
"We are hoping you will have a wonderful future. The Garcias, Long Island City."
他們花了三天時間  來整理這些郵件
It took Charlie and Yvonne three days to open all their mail.
結果他們發現  紐約城給了他們六十萬美元小費
And when they were done, New York had given them a $600,000 tip.
查理又高興地回到了警隊
Charlie happily went back to the force.
「物業產權證」
伊芳贖回了她的咖啡館
Yvonne got her coffee shop back.
艾迪只找到一份開出租車的工作
Eddie could only get work driving a cab.
還有穆麗兒  她嫁給了傑克·格羅斯
And Muriel. She married Jack Gross...
那傢伙捲走了她所有的錢後  就逃到了國外
...who cleaned out their checking account and fled the country.
穆麗兒現在和她母親住在布朗克斯區  她在一家美甲店裏打工
Muriel lives in the Bronx with her mother now and works in a nail salon.
在查理  穆麗兒和伊芳生活的這座城市裏
Charlie, Muriel and Yvonne all lived in a city...
人們每天都期盼著奇跡發生  有時候  奇跡確實發生了
...where people prayed for miracles every day. And sometimes they happened.
「警察迎娶女招待」
劇 終
謝 謝 觀 賞